

ALEX AYSO





Executive Summary

Hi I'm Alex, 26 years of age. I'm a software engineer with 5 years of experience. I specialized on mobile development and also knowledgeable in backend development and dev ops. I am now loving Flutter for building mobile applications and also web applications. And right now I am actively exploring and integrating firebase and google cloud services to my Flutter projects. I also had experience developing and deploying API's. And done some CI/CD workflows. I am also very interested on AI and machine learning and if I have spare time I always read or watch any news related to it and also create personal projects using or integrating AI . I am highly motivated and positive person.

Areas of Expertise

- Flutter development
- Android Studio (Java and Kotlin)
- Xcode
- Backend development (NodeJS)
- Google cloud functions
- REST API integrations
- Firebase setup and integrations
- AWS Cloud
- SQL and NoSQL database
- · CI/CD
- Unit tests
- Playstore and Appstore distributions
- Git

Education:

Bachelor Of Science In Information Technology

Arellano University

Reach me at:

Mobile: 09761215840 alex.ayso04@gmail.com alex.ayso@yahoo.com linkedin.com/in/alex-ayso-34a67317a/

Work Experience

FULLSTACK SOFTAWARE DEVELOPER

MekaSales Inc. - Metro Manila Sept 11, 2023 - Present

Lead the technical implementation of company's projects. Created POC for target clients. Involved in the entire development initiative. From technology selections and implementation. Exposed in technologies such as AWS Cloud integrations, Flutter, Firebase, NodeJs, React, CI/CD pipelines.

FLUTTER DEVELOPER (Freelance)

Upwork - Utah

Feb 09, 2023 - May 20, 2023

Created a mobile app for client on Upwork. This app is a POC to showcase most important features. The app is a social media where users can create, invite and plan events. They can also communicate using built in chat features within the app. This is built using Flutter, Google cloud services and Firebase for backend. The app was built within 3 months.

APP DEVELOPER LEAD

CARKETA - Utah June 2020 - Jan 2023

Lead the app development for a US based company. Developed and deployed apps such as Carketa a condition report app to help user and dealership manage inventory and track information about the vehicles and Carketa valuation tool an app that help's the user evaluate a vehicle by knowing their market price, vehicle history and more. Here I was exposed in technologies like Flutter, Flutter web, Firebase (Auth, Firestore, Realtime db, Analytics, Storage, Hosting and machine learning), Appstore IOS app build and deployment, Playstore app build and deployment.

MOBILE DEVELOPER

SD Solutions - Ortigas (WFH) August 24, 2021 - September 30, 2022

Lead the mobile app development team for multiple projects. Such as online food and grocery delivery app both for rider and client. This app is basically like grab or food panda. Exposed to technologies such as Firebase(messaging, firestore, hosting, cloud functions, analytics, distribution). Also built small projects for and revamps for existing projects. Introduced a proper flow from planning, development up to distributions and new technologies to the team.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Stratpoint Technologies, Inc. - Mandaluyong Feb 2020 - September 2021

Developed a project management app an the internal project of the company using Flutter. Also involved and lead some of client projects such as GlobeOne Flutter POC, GlobeOneX, TMX, and GOMO app. Here I was exposed in technologies like Flutter, Firebase, GraphQL.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

IT Managers, Inc. - Makati Feb 2019 - Feb 2020

Outsourced to a bank to help develop a digital bank onboarding. Developed a eKYC app that has a ability to scan face liveliness and id verification. Here I was exposed in technologies like Azure and AWS cloud, CI/CD setup, backend development using Java Spring framework, Android development JAVA/Kotlin.

APP DEVELOPER PACIFIC DATA RESOURCES, INC. - Makati Sep 2017 - Jan 2019 Developed native GIS mobile survey application for a telecommunication company. Here I was exposed in Android development, OSMDroid integrations, geolocation.